https://www.nelson-atkins.org/privacy-policy/

Home
Search Visit & SeeHours, Parking & MoreAccessibilityCollectionsExhibitionsSearch Collection@HomeDo & LearnClassesCalendarEventsFestivalsCommunity ProgramsConservationEducatorsLibraryToursShop & EatShop OnlineMuseum StoreRozzelle CourtQuay CoffeeGive & SupportCareers & InternshipsDonate TodayGet InvolvedWays to GiveMembershipLearn MoreJoin / RenewMember ExperienceFrequently Asked Questions
Privacy PolicyGENERALYour privacy is important to us. This privacy policy is intended to give you confidence in the privacy and security of the personal information we obtain from you whether you are using the Nelson-Atkins’ website (the “Website”), or transacting business with us over the phone, at our museum store, Information Services desk or Rozzelle Court restaurant (our “Services”).COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATIONWhen you use our Website or Services, you may be asked for personally identifiable information such as your name, address, date of birth, email address, telephone number.By giving us such information, you will need to consent to our using it in the manner described in this policy.You may withdraw your consent at any time by emailing us at ask@nelson-atkins.org. We will return or destroy your personal information within five days of receipt of your withdrawal of consent.Cookie information, pages you have requested and your IP address may also be recorded by us and/or third parties from your browser as set out in this policy.USE OF PERFORMANCE DATAThe Nelson-Atkins will use performance data, including performance statistics, bug fixes and other similar data (“Performance Data”) uploaded to our Website or acquired through our Services. The Nelson-Atkins may use such Performance Data in any way, including, but not limited to, using, editing, altering, reproducing, publishing and/or distributing the Performance Data for any purpose, commercial or otherwise, provided that such Performance Data is stripped of all personally identifiable information.USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATIONWe use personal information to allow us to process your service requests, provide access to privileged areas of the Website or Museum, send out newsletters, personalize your visit to our Website, personalize your use of our Services, and enable us to improve the Services we offer. We may occasionally carry out market research and send you details of offers that we think may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive such information, please e-mail ask@nelson-atkins.org or, alternatively, when we send you an e-mail, it will contain a provision for you to opt out of receiving any further information from us.DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATIONWe may provide information about you to our employees and agents in order to administer any accounts, Services and services provided to you by the Nelson-Atkins.We will not disclose your personal information to any third party unless you have consented to such disclosure or where we are required to do so by law. Should you breach our terms and conditions or terms of use or if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, we may disclose your information to a relevant authority. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Any disclosure of personal information will be strictly controlled and made fully in accordance with current U.S. law.If you are visiting the Nelson-Atkins to attend an event sponsored by a 3rd party (another organization that has rented the museum facility for their own customers), personal information collected by the Nelson-Atkins on their behalf will be available to them and may used according to their privacy policies.COOKIESCookies are small data files that a website you visit may save on your computer or handheld device that usually includes an anonymous unique identifier. Our Websites and those of our Services may use cookies for user authentication, keeping track of your preferences, promotional campaigns, tracking our audience size and traffic patterns, and in certain other cases. We may include small graphic images in our email messages and newsletters to determine whether the messages were opened and the links were viewed.If you do not wish cookies to be placed on your PC or handheld device, then they can be disabled in your web browser. The option to do so is normally found in your browser’s “security settings” section. Please note that permanently disabling cookies in your browser may hinder your use of our Website.SECURITYAll security on our Website is treated seriously. Where applicable, we undertake security steps, including use of SSL technology, on our back-end systems that store customer account information and to protect data transmissions. However, this is not a guarantee that such data transmissions cannot be accessed, altered or deleted due to firewall or other security software failures.If you have any further concerns about security, please email us at ask@nelson-atkins.org.POLICY CHANGESChanges in this policy will be posted on our Website. You are advised to check our Website regularly to view our most recent privacy policy. X Search for:
